We're now ready to take a look at
现在我们已经准备好了解
the Deep Q-Learning Algorithm and implement it on our own.
深度 Q 学习算法并自己实现它
There are two main processes that are interleaved in this algorithm.
该算法中有两个交错的主要流程
One, is where we sample the environment by performing actions
一个流程是对环境取样 方法是执行动作
and store away the observed experienced tuples in a replay memory.
并以回放存储器的形式存储观察的经验元组
The other is where we select the small batch of tuples from this memory,
另一个流程是随机地从该存储器中选择一小批元组
randomly, and learn from that batch using a gradient descent update step.
并使用梯度下降更新步骤从该批次中学习规律
These two processes are not directly dependent on each other.
这两个流程并非直接相互依赖
So, you could perform multiple sampling steps then one learning step,
因此 你可以完成多个取样步骤 然后完成一个学习步骤
or even multiple learning steps with different random batches.
或者具有不同随机批次的多个学习步骤
The rest of the algorithm is designed to support these steps.
该算法的剩余步骤旨在支持这些步骤
In the beginning you need to initialize an empty replay
一开始你需要初始化空的回放存储器
memory D. Note that memory is finite,
注意存储器是有限的
so you may want to use something like a circular Q
因此你可能需要使用循环 Q
that retains the N most recent experience tuples.
保留最近 n 个经验元组
Then, you also need to initialize the parameters or weights of your neural network.
然后 你还需要初始化神经网络的参数或权重
There are certain best practices that you can use, for instance,
你可以采取一些最佳做法
sample the weights randomly from a normal distribution with
例如 从正态分布中随机抽取一些权重
variance equal to two by the number of inputs to each neuron.
方差等于每个神经元输入数量的两倍
These initialization methods are typically available in
Keras 和 TensorFlow 等现代深度学习库
modern deep learning libraries like Keras and TensorFlow,
通常都包含这些初始化方法
so you won't need to implement them yourself.
因此你不需要自己实现这些方法
To use the fixed Q targets technique,
要采用固定 Q 目标技巧
you need a second set of parameters w- which you can initialize to w. Now,
你需要第二组参数 w- 可以初始化为 w
remember that the specific algorithm was designed to work with video games.
注意 这一特定算法专门用于视频游戏
So, for each episode and each time step t within that episode you observe
对于每个阶段和该阶段中的每个时间步 t
a raw screen image or input frame x
你会观察原始屏幕图像或输入帧 xt
t which you need to convert to grayscale crop to a square size,
并需要将其转换为灰阶形式 剪切为正方形 等等
etc.. Also, in order to capture
此外 为了捕获时间关系
temporal relationships you can stack a few input frames to build each state vector.
你可以堆叠一些输入帧以构建每个状态向量
Let's denote this pre-processing and stacking operation by the function phi,
我们用函数 phi 表示这个预处理和堆叠操作
which takes a sequence of frames and produces some combined representation.
该函数会接收一系列的帧并形成组合表示法
Note that if we want to stack say four frames
注意 如果我们要堆叠帧 例如四个帧
will have to do something special for the first, three time steps.
则需要对前三个时间步进行特殊处理
For instance, we can treat those missing frames as blank,
例如 我们可以将这些丢失的帧当做空帧
or just used copies of the first frame,
使用第一帧的副本
or we can just skip storing the experience tuples till we get a complete sequence.
或跳过存储经验帧这一步 直到获得完整的序列
In practice, you won't be able to run the learning step immediately.
在现实中 你无法立即运行学习步骤
You will need to wait till you have sufficient number of tuples in memory.
需要等待 直到存储器中有足够数量的元组
Note that we do not clear out the memory after each episode,
注意 在每个阶段之后 我们不清空存储器
this enables us to recall and build batches of experiences from across episodes.
这样可以跨阶段地回忆和形成批量经验
There are many other techniques and optimizations that are used in the DQN paper,
DQN 论文中用到了很多其他技巧和优化方式
such as reward clipping,
例如奖励裁剪 误差裁剪
error clipping, storing past actions as part of the state vector,
将过去的动作存储为状态向量的一部分
dealing with terminal states,
处理终止状态
digging epsilon over time, et cetera.
挖掘一段时间内的 ϵ 等
I encourage you to read the paper,
建议你在自己实现该算法之前
especially the methods section before trying to implement the algorithm yourself.
阅读这篇论文 尤其是方法部分
Note that you may need to choose which techniques you apply
注意 你可能需要选择应用哪些技巧
and adapt them for different types of environments.
并针对不同类型的环境调整这些技巧